Mohsen Koorani Maskan

Back-End Developer (.Net)

+98 910 988 3120

Male / Single

- Mkm.Koorani@outlook.com
- KevinMKM.github.io
- Karaj, Alborz, Iran
- linkedin.com/in/MohsenKooraniMaskan

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Back-end developer with over 5 years of experience in a top-notch organization and a creative person with the ability of managing the projects and participate in teamwork. Skilled in .Net (Framework, Core), Entity Framework / Core, C#, OOP, SOLID, Design Patterns, SQL Server, UML Modeling, reporting with "StimulSoft", making documentation, Familiar with the implementation of human resource processes and very eager to learn new technologies.

Core Competencies and Skills:

.Net (Framework, Core), Entity Framework / Core, C#, SQL Server, UML Modeling, StimulSoft

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pendar Ideas (Tehran, Tehran, Iran) - Back-end developer

June 2018 - Present

I'm honored to work as a part of such an awesome team from all over Iran. my tasks and achievements are:

- Completing more than 500 successful issues including research and development of new features, finding and fixing bugs (based on Gitlab VCS).
- Design and development of a framework to produce various reports in StimulSoft.
- Design and development of various reports for human resource management applications. (Logics and corresponding output in StimulSoft).
- Design and development of a windows application to extract data from time attendance devices (different types of devices) and upload into the company's product database.
- Improve company's old designs and development of company products.
- Use SQL file manager concepts to improve file storage of all company products.
- Management of servers and databases of the company's products.
- Design and development of a framework to using Hangfire in the company's products.
- Designing and developing the wizard and widget concepts in UML models and related engines.
- Create and improve UML models of company's products by Magic Draw.
- Create documentation of the company's codes and products in Microsoft Azure.
- Write e2e tests with selenium framework and unit tests for different parts of the company's products.

Freelance - Aerospace and IT Projects

2014 - June 2018

- Over 200 projects in Aerospace Engineering field (Software and Coding), Web Designing (HTML and CSS) and university C# Projects.
- Holding more than 10 software and programming courses (Aerospace Engineering and C#).
- Translate academic and scientific papers (English to Persian).

Aria Sabokbal (Urmia, West Azerbaijan, Iran) – *Industrial Designer*

2014 - 2017

I'm honored to work as designer and after 2 years as the head of design department. my tasks are:

- Scientific design and production of various parts of light aircraft (2 to 8 people).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Application SW - SSMS, Magic Draw, Stimulsoft.

Programming Skills – C#, WPF/ Windows Form, .Net (Framework/Core), Entity Framework/ Core, ASP.Net (MVC/ Core) – Web Api, T-SQL, Fluent Api, OOP-Design Patterns and Solid Principles, Git, Nuget PM.

Other Skills – UML and Data Modeling, Unit and E2E Testing.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Programming – C# (Fundamentals, Windows Form), Python, MATLAB, Maple, Fortran, Abaqus UDF.

Software – Catia, Abaqus, MATLAB, Maple.

EDUCATION

K. N. T. University of Technology, Tehran, Tehran – MSc in Aerospace-Structural Engineering 2017 – 2020

- Academics: 3.6/4 GPA with an A in Composite Structures, Adv. Structural Analysis, Adv. Structural Dynamics, FEM, Aeroelastic and Optimization.
- Honors: Ranked 1st in the class of 2017, Aerospace Engineering Structural Engineering Dept. of K. N. T. university of technology.
- Teacher Assistant: Adv. Structural Dynamics, Adv. Structural Analysis, Adv. Composite Structures, Adv. Finite Element Methods (FEM), Mechanics of Materials.
- MSc Thesis: Progressive damages analysis due to mechanical and thermal loads on composite laminates (analysis by Abaqus commercial software and a general and innovative python script for simulate progress of damage and failure).

Urmia University of Technology, Urmia, West Azerbaijan – **BSc in Aerospace Engineering** 2013 – 2017

- Academics: 3.3/4 GPA with an A in Aerodynamic, Propulsion, Control, Heat Transfer.
- Honors: Ranked 3rd in the class of 2013, Aerospace Engineering Dept. of Urmia university of technology.
- Leadership: Secretary of the association of Inventors and Researchers of Urmia university of technology.
- BSc Thesis: Improving diesel engine performance by controlling cavitation in injector nozzles (analysis by Ansys - Fluent commercial software).

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Leadership Experience:

- Head of the association of Inventors and researchers of Urmia university of technology, 2015 2017.
- Manager of red crescent society of urmia university of technology, 2014 2017.

ADDITIONAL

Personal/Other:

- 4 Year teaching experience in academic software's and programming languages
- Languages: Persian (Native), English (B1)
- Requested salary per month: 200,000,000 IRR